<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - tandoori</title>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/tandoori/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/tandoori.html"/>
 <updated>2018-04-05T01:54:57+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/tandoori.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Color of Tandoori Chicken</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tandoori/cooking/food-coloring/2017/12/15/color-of-tandoori-chicken.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-15T16:50:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/tandoori/cooking/food-coloring/2017/12/15/color-of-tandoori-chicken</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e1/Chickentandoori.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tandoori chicken is a favorite dish that is served as a stand alone dish or
along with Briyani. It goes well with Mutton Briyani or Kushkaa. If you find
that meat in your briyani is sparse, you may buy a tandoori along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good thing about Tandoori is unlike Chicken 65 that is fried in oil, this
one uses very less oil. First chicken cut in right places and is marinated in
certain type of masalas for hours, this makes sure the meat become tender, juicy
and absorbs the flavoring. Next the chicken is lowered in coal fired oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coal fire is important as coal has and adds an unique flavor to the dish. Coal
on burning emits no water vapor. Tandoori is formed when water evaporates from
the chicken and is replaced by oils in the chicken. Occasionally the chef might
take the chicken out and brush oil on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here in this blog we are talking about the color of the tandoori. Is it reddish
like the image above or is it brownish as shown below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tandoori_chicken_right_color.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you say its like the first image you must watch out. To say the truth, food
coloring is no way associated with taste of the food. Its just to make the food
attractive to look. Next there is issue of health, its gossiped that coloring
is not good for health. So who knows?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What we advise people is to goto restaurants that serve tandoori in which
natural color, i.e kinda brown comes out and not the fake red. Possibly long
term ingestion of food coloring might prove bad for your health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you know a restaurant that serves Tandoori with natural colors? Then do let
people know by commenting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://articles.mercola.com/sites/articles/archive/2011/02/24/are-you-or-your-family-eating-toxic-food-dyes.aspx&quot;&gt;Are You or Your Family Eating Toxic Food Dyes?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
