<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - barbeque</title>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/barbeque/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/barbeque.html"/>
 <updated>2018-03-29T08:34:09+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/barbeque.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Review of Seashell Velacherry</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/restaurant/review/chennai/velacherry/barbeque/2018/03/02/review-of-seashell-velacherry.html"/>
   <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/restaurant/review/chennai/velacherry/barbeque/2018/03/02/review-of-seashell-velacherry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img-cdn.eveningflavors.com/EvfImages/Restaurant/Chennai/22802/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nammasamayal had been in Sea shell a while ago, and in this blog we wish to talk
about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went on a Saturday, we got a parking for our car quiet easily which was a
surprise. We went to the restaurant upstairs, the first thing we noticed was the
noise. Though Seashell is an expensive restaurant, the noise level was really
high. People were talking all around and there was no noise absorption surface
around. So the ambiance was not what we expected from a good branded restaurant.
In Greames road Sea Shell, we had separating walls that muted sounds a bit,
over here in Velacherry it was open and was disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets come to the food now. We ordered Chicken Briyani, Mutton Briyani and a
barbecue platter (which is shown below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/seashell_barbeque_platter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platter came early before Briyani. I see this trend in today
 where the butlers are told to serve the side dish first. Lets say that I had
 ordered a Mutton Briyani with Chicken 65, the Chicken 65 is served first, so
 I start to chew on it, by the time the briyani arrives, I would be low on the
 side dish and may possibly order another one. Nice trick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we ordered a huge platter, it had barbecued chicken that was good,
 the prawn and mutton was okay too, but the fish barbecued… well, it wasn’t
 nice. If you notice the chicken it had food coloring, which I don’t like, but
 thats how restaurants serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barbecue platter also came with barbecued paneer and other veggies, which
 were okay. The barbecues did complement briyani well. I did not taste the
 Chicken Briyani, I had the mutton. The mutton was really soft and good, but
 the briyani, hmmm… it wasn’t good enough, it wasn’t bad either. The best thing
 was a red chutney they give you in a small cup which you can garnish your
 barbecue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall for a restaurant that charges you extra for an extra mayonnaise, Sea Shell
 is only below okay. They could do a lot more for what they charge.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
