<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-30T23:39:22+05:30</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Namma Samayal</title><subtitle>A Blog, Critique about food, restaurants and foodie events in Chennai.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nethili Meen Kulambu</title><link href="/2018/03/30/nethili-meen-kulambu.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nethili Meen Kulambu" /><published>2018-03-30T23:28:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-30T23:28:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/30/nethili-meen-kulambu</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/30/nethili-meen-kulambu.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nethili-kulambu-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preparation Time :&lt;/strong&gt; 10 mins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cooking Time :&lt;/strong&gt; 30 mins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Serves :&lt;/strong&gt; 5 to 6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anchovies / Nethili Meen – 3 cups cleaned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coconut Oil – 2 tblspn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mustard Seeds / Kaduku – 1 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fenugreek Seeds / Vendayam – 1/2 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curry leaves – 1 spring + 1 spring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onion – 1 large sliced thinly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tomato – 2 large chopped finely&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brinjal – 1 large cubed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mango – 1 small cubed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chilli powder – 2 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pepper powder – 1 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coriander powder / Malli podi – 1 tblspn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turmeric powder / Manjal podi – 1 tsp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tamarind Pulp – 3 tblspn (Click here for recipe)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;method&quot;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a kadai with oil, when it is hot add in mustard, fenugreek and curry leaves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in onions and saute till it turns light golden.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now add in tomatoes and saute till oil separates. Add in salt and mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now add in turmeric, chilli, coriander and pepper powder. Mix well.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in brinjal, mangoes and mix well. Pour in some water and cover the pan. Cook for 10 mins till the brinjal is cooked and the sauce is thick.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add in tamarind pulp and mix well. Cover again and cook till oil separates.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now add in anchovies and cook for 5 to 10 mins.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Throw in a handful of curry leaves and switch off the flame. Cover the pan till serving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Serve over rice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">White Chocolate Cheesecake with Raspberry Swirl</title><link href="/2018/03/30/white_chocolate_cheesecake_with_raspberry_swirl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="White Chocolate Cheesecake with Raspberry Swirl" /><published>2018-03-30T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-30T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/30/white_chocolate_cheesecake_with_raspberry_swirl</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/30/white_chocolate_cheesecake_with_raspberry_swirl.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/White_Chocolate_Cheesecake_with_Raspberry_Swirl&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-crust&quot;&gt;For the crust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;15 graham crackers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp. sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/8 tsp. kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tbsp. butter, melted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-raspberry-sauce&quot;&gt;For the raspberry sauce&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 oz. raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp. sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-cheesecake&quot;&gt;For the cheesecake&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 oz. white chocolate, melted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 8-oz. packages cream cheese, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/4 c. sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp. kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp. pure vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 large eggs, at room temperature&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4 c. sour cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 c. heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 7:10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:40&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the crust: Butter a 9” springform pan and wrap bottom and sides of pan in double layer of aluminum foil. Set rack in middle of oven and preheat oven to 350°.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In food processor or blender, grind graham crackers into fine crumbs. Add sugar and salt and pulse to combine. Transfer to medium bowl, add butter, and use fork or fingers to blend mixture until crumbs are evenly moist. Press into bottom and about a third of the way up sides of springform pan, then freeze pan, 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place pan on baking sheet and bake crust, 10 minutes. Set on rack to cool and reduce oven temperature to 325°.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the raspberry sauce: In food processor or blender, purée berries and sugar until smooth, about 30 seconds. Pour through fine-mesh strainer set over small bowl, pushing on berries to release any juices; discard solids. Set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make the cheesecake: Bring medium saucepan or tea kettle full of water to boil.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a clean, dry metal bowl set over a pan of barely simmering water, melt white chocolate, stirring until smooth. Remove from heat and set aside to cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl using a hand mixer or in the bowl of a stand mixer using the whisk attachment, beat cream cheese on medium, scraping down bowl as necessary, until completely smooth, 3 to 4 minutes. Add sugar and salt and beat, scraping down bowl as necessary, until smooth and fluffy, 3 to 4 minutes. Add vanilla and beat for 30 seconds. Add eggs, 1 at a time, beating for 1 minute after each addition and scraping down bowl as necessary. Add melted white chocolate, sour cream, and heavy cream and beat on low until fully incorporated and completely smooth, about 1 minute.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour cheesecake batter into cooled crust and smooth top. Drop teaspoons of raspberry sauce all over top of cheesecake. Use a wooden skewer or toothpick to swirl sauce into batter. Place cheesecake in deep roasting pan and set on middle rack of oven. Carefully pour enough boiling water into roasting pan to come about halfway up sides of springform pan. Bake until top is just starting to brown and crack, about 1 hour and 30 minutes. Turn off oven, prop door open with wooden spoon, and let cheesecake slowly cool in water bath for 1 hour.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove roasting pan from oven, then carefully lift springform pan out of water and remove foil. Set cheesecake on a rack and let come to room temperature. Once completely cool, loosely cover cheesecake with plastic wrap and refrigerate, 4 hours, or preferably overnight. When ready to serve, carefully remove sides of springform pan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cheesy Tomato Soup</title><link href="/2018/03/29/cheesy_tomato_soup.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cheesy Tomato Soup" /><published>2018-03-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/29/cheesy_tomato_soup</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/29/cheesy_tomato_soup.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Cheesy_Tomato_Soup&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp. unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 small French baguette, sliced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Garlic clove, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 carrots, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 celery stalks, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;28 oz. crushed tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 c. vegetable stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 c. grated Gruyere cheese&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. fresh parsley, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:35&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400 degrees F. Spread bread with 2 tablespoons butter. On a large baking sheet, toast bread until golden, 2 minutes; set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, melt remaining tablespoon butter in a large pot over medium heat. Add onion, garlic, carrots, and celery and cook until tender, 2 to 3 minutes. Add tomatoes, stock, 1 teaspoon salt, and 1/2 teaspoon black pepper. Bring to a boil and simmer 15 minutes. Puree soup using an immersion blender or carefully pour into a blender and process in batches. Stir in cream.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place four ovenproof soup bowls or ramekins onto a sheet pan. Divide soup among bowls and top each with 2 croutons and 1/2 cup cheese. Cook until cheese is melted and bubbling, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Garnish with parsley and serve immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beef and Guinness Pies</title><link href="/2018/03/29/beef_and_guinness_pies.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beef and Guinness Pies" /><published>2018-03-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/29/beef_and_guinness_pies</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/29/beef_and_guinness_pies.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Beef_and_Guinness_Pies&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 lb. beef chuck or stew meat trimmed and cut into 1” pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 tbsp. flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp. olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 shallots, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 large portobello mushrooms (about 14 oz.), cut into 1” pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large carrots, cut into 1/4” pieces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves garlic, smashed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 celery stalk, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Sprig Fresh Thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 14.9 oz. can Guinness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 c. low-sodium beef broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tbsp. unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 oz. bittersweet chocolate, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sheets frozen puff pastry 9from a 17.3 oz. package), thawed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large egg, beaten&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 3:40&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:55&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, toss the beef with 2 tablespoons flour and 1/2 teaspoon each salt and pepper. Heat 1 tablespoon oil in a large pot or Dutch oven over medium heat. In two batches, brown the beef on all sides, about 5 minutes total (add 1 tablespoon oil for the second batch); transfer to a plate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add the remaining 1 tablespoon oil to the pot. Add the shallots, mushrooms, carrots, garlic, celery and thyme and cook, stirring occasionally, until beginning to soften, about 5 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return the beef to the pot with the Guinness and beef broth (make sure beef and vegetables are covered completely, adding additional water if necessary). Simmer gently, stirring occasionally, until beef is tender, 1 1/2 to 2 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Once the beef is done, strain the cooking liquid into a large measuring cup (you should still have 3 to 4 cups). Return the beef and vegetables to the pot, discarding the thyme. Melt the butter with 1/2 cup cooking liquid in a medium saucepan over medium heat. Stir in the remaining 3 tablespoons flour to form a smooth paste. Gradually whisk in the rest of the strained cooking liquid and simmer until slightly thickened, 4 to 5 minutes. Add the chocolate and stir to melt. Pour the sauce over the beef and vegetables and let cool.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Arrange one rack on the bottom of the oven and heat to 350 degrees F. Working with one sheet at a time, on a lightly floured surface, roll out the pastry into a 14” square and cut out two 8” circles and two 6” circles. Fit the 8” cutouts into the bottom and up the sides of two 6” pie plates. Repeat with the remaining sheet. Divide the beef mixture among the pie plates (about 1 1/2 cups per plate). use the 6” cutouts to cover each pie, pinching the edges to seal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lightly brush the pastry with the egg, then use a sharp knife to cut 2 diagonal slits in the top of each piece of pastry. Place the pies on a rimmed baking sheet and bake on the lowest rack until the pastry is puffed and golden brown, 45 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mutton Briyani in Hotel Crescent Adyar</title><link href="/2018/03/27/mutton-briyani-in-hotel-crescent-adyar.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mutton Briyani in Hotel Crescent Adyar" /><published>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/27/mutton-briyani-in-hotel-crescent-adyar</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/27/mutton-briyani-in-hotel-crescent-adyar.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mutton_briyani_in_cresent_adyar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Namma Samayal, we went to a hotel, in fact a restaurant in Adyar called Crescent. I had mutton Briyani there and this is my review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say it in short, avoid eating mutton briyani in this hotel, as this was our experience. The hotel was fairly neat, just like any Chennai restaurant the seating was tight, the tables were bit small. This hotel is in basement, the cooling was suboptimal, the air-conditioner was not working properly or possibly was not adequate, it was assisted by a wall mounted fan. So if you want a good ambiance this is not a great restaurant for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered a mutton briyani, the supervisor asked weather I want ordinary or Kerala style, I asked for ordinary one. It costs Rs 175/- actually pretty expensive. When I got the briyani, I was disappointed, the briyani looked white like Kerala style. When I ate it, I was more disappointed as there was no flavor in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was really bland. With briyani they serve onion raitha, and a kurma. The kurma had no meaty flavor, the briyani was so  so bland that it had to go along with the kurma, else it was just meat in rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must talk about the meat, the meat was cooked well, and it was perfect, every bone that had edible marrow was cracked properly so that I can open it and eat it. The meat was tender. But the briyani was horrible. No meat flavor in rice, the rice was not basmathi, I wonder weather they cooked the rice with mutton?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quantity of the briyani too was low, but the ratio of meat to rice was high compared to many hotels and was acceptable. Possibly is this is another briyani variety and I am mistaken? I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel is named Crescent and seems to be run by Muslims (in Muslim run hotels I expect really good quality briyani). In Chennai, one thinks pulao is briyani. Briyani is a dish where rice and meat are cooked in half independent of each other, finally they are mixed and cooked full. Briyani will be far less spicy than pulao. I don’t know if I am wrong in judging this hotel, as my mind thinks pulao is briyani, but the experience was not good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wish the service could be improved, I asked for extra kurma and raitha to some how complete the ordered, but it came pretty late even when the hotel was almost empty.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="restaurant" /><category term="review" /><category term="adyar" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Asian Noodle Bowls with Steak and Snow Peas</title><link href="/2018/03/27/asian_noodle_bowls_with_steak_and_snow_peas.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Asian Noodle Bowls with Steak and Snow Peas" /><published>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/27/asian_noodle_bowls_with_steak_and_snow_peas</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/27/asian_noodle_bowls_with_steak_and_snow_peas.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Asian_Noodle_Bowls_with_Steak_and_Snow_Peas&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coarse salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ground pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 package soba (Japanese buckwheat noodles)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 skirt steak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lb. snow peas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp. soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. unsalted peanuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:25&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a pot of boiling salted water, cook noodles until al dente. Drain; set aside.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a large skillet over medium-high. Season steak with salt and pepper. Cook (in batches if necessary), turning once, until medium-rare, 2 to 6 minutes per side. Transfer steak to a cutting board, and loosely tent with aluminum foil (reserve skillet with juices).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add snow peas to skillet, and toss with juices. Cook on medium-high heat, tossing occasionally, until crisp-tender, 2 to 3 minutes. Add noodles, soy sauce, and 2 tablespoons water; cook until warmed through, about 20 seconds. Transfer to serving bowls. Slice steak; place on top of noodles, and add any accumulated juices. Scatter with peanuts, and serve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">40 Cloves of Garlic Chicken</title><link href="/2018/03/27/40_cloves_of_garlic_chicken.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="40 Cloves of Garlic Chicken" /><published>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-27T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/27/40_cloves_of_garlic_chicken</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/27/40_cloves_of_garlic_chicken.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/40_Cloves_of_Garlic_Chicken&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lb. bone-in skin-on chicken thighs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;40 garlic cloves, peeled&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 c. dry white wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 c. low-sodium chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp. unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12 oz. penne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. chopped parsley&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:40&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large skillet over medium-high heat, warm oil. Dry chicken thighs with paper towels and season with salt and pepper. Sear chicken skin side down until brown, 5 minutes. Flip over and cook for 1 minute more, then transfer to a plate skin side up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add garlic and cook for 5 minutes over medium heat. Stir in wine and broth, using a wooden spoon to scrape up the brown bits. Season with salt and pepper and add chicken, skin side up. Bring to a boil and simmer on low until chicken is cooked through and sauce is thickened, 20 minutes. Stir in butter and heavy cream.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, in a large pot of salted boiling water, cook pasta according to package directions until al dente. Drain, reserving 1/2 cup pasta water.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transfer penne, pasta water, and parsley into the pan and mix well. Add chicken  and serve immediately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lemon Poppy Seed Cake</title><link href="/2018/03/24/lemon_poppy_seed_cake.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lemon Poppy Seed Cake" /><published>2018-03-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/24/lemon_poppy_seed_cake</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/24/lemon_poppy_seed_cake.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Lemon_Poppy_Seed_Cake&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-cake&quot;&gt;For the cake&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cooking spray, for pan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 c. (2 sticks) butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 c. sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp. pure vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 c. all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 tbsp. cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2 tsp. baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp. kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 c. buttermilk (or sour cream)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. freshly squeezed lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tbsp. lemon zest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp. poppy seeds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-the-cream-cheese-frosting&quot;&gt;For the cream cheese frosting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 (8-oz) blocks cream cheese, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 c. (1 stick) Butter, softened&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 c. powdered sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tbsp. pure vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tsp. freshly squeezed lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp. kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon Slices, for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lemon zest, for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 1:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350° and line a 9-x-13” baking pan with parchment paper. Grease with cooking spray. In a large bowl using a hand mixer (or in the bowl of a stand mixer), beat together butter and sugar until light and fluffy. Add eggs one at a time, beating well after each addition. Add vanilla and mix until combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In another large bowl whisk together flour, cornstarch, baking powder, and salt. Add flour mixture to the wet ingredients, beating until just combined. Pour in the buttermilk and lemon juice and mix until fully incorporated. Add lemon zest and and poppy seeds and stir until just combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour batter into prepared baking pan. Bake until slightly golden on top and a toothpick inserted into the middle comes out clean, about 30 minutes. Remove from pan and let cool completely.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a large bowl, beat together cream cheese and butter until light and fluffy. Add powdered sugar, vanilla, lemon juice, and salt and beat until smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frost cake with frosting and garnish with lemon slices and zest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jack-O’-Lantern Stuffed Peppers</title><link href="/2018/03/24/jack-o'-lantern_stuffed_peppers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jack-O'-Lantern Stuffed Peppers" /><published>2018-03-24T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-24T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/24/jack-o'-lantern_stuffed_peppers</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/24/jack-o'-lantern_stuffed_peppers.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Jack-O'-Lantern_Stuffed_Peppers&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 orange bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extra-virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 Onion, finely chopped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 garlic cloves, minced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tsp. chili powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 lb. ground beef&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 c. cooked white rice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 c. chicken stock, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 (15 oz) can fire-roasted tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 c. shredded Monterey Jack, divided&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 1:00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 350°.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cut off (and reserve) the top of each pepper. Remove and discard the cores and seeds. Using a sharp paring knife, carve a Jack O’Lantern face into each pepper. Drizzle the inside of each pepper with olive oil and season generously with salt and pepper. Place the peppers upright in a large baking dish along with the pepper tops.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat a tablespoon of olive oil in a large nonstick skillet. Sauté onions until soft, about 5 minutes. Add garlic and cook until fragrant, about 30 seconds. Add beef and sauté until browned and cooked through, breaking up the meat with a wooden spoon. Turn off the heat and drain the fat.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Return skillet to stovetop over medium heat. Season with salt and pepper to taste and stir in the chili powder. Add the fire-roasted tomatoes, 1/2 cup chicken stock, cooked rice and 3/4 cup of cheese. Stir until the mixture is evenly combined.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Divide rice and beef mixture between the hollowed out peppers. Top with cheese.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pour remaining 1/2 cup chicken stock into pan. Cover with foil and bake for about 30 minutes. Remove the foil and cook for another 10-15 minutes, until the peppers are tender and the cheese is melted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Low-Carb Breakfast Pizza</title><link href="/2018/03/23/low-carb_breakfast_pizza.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Low-Carb Breakfast Pizza" /><published>2018-03-23T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2018-03-23T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>/2018/03/23/low-carb_breakfast_pizza</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2018/03/23/low-carb_breakfast_pizza.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Low-Carb_Breakfast_Pizza&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 large eggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 1/2 c. shredded mozzarella, divided&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 grated Parmesan, plus more for garnish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;kosher salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 tsp. dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pinch red pepper flakes (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tbsp. pizza sauce (or marinara)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 c. mini pepperoni&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 Green Bell Pepper, chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:30&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prep Time:&lt;/strong&gt; 0:05&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Servings:&lt;/strong&gt; 
					1&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;procedure&quot;&gt;Procedure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400° and line a baking sheet with parchment paper. In a medium bowl, combine eggs, 2 cups mozzarella, and parmesan. Stir until combined, then season with salt, pepper, oregano and red pepper flakes. Spread mixture into a ½” thick round on baking sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake until lightly golden, about 12 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spread pizza sauce on top of baked crust. Top with remaining mozzarella, pepperoni, and bell pepper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bake until cheese is melted and crust is crispy, about 10 minutes more. Sprinkle with Parmesan, if using, before serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>