<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - velacherry</title>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/velacherry/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/velacherry.html"/>
 <updated>2018-04-07T17:09:41+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/velacherry.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Review of Seashell Velacherry</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/restaurant/review/chennai/velacherry/barbeque/2018/03/02/review-of-seashell-velacherry.html"/>
   <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/restaurant/review/chennai/velacherry/barbeque/2018/03/02/review-of-seashell-velacherry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://img-cdn.eveningflavors.com/EvfImages/Restaurant/Chennai/22802/1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nammasamayal had been in Sea shell a while ago, and in this blog we wish to talk
about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We went on a Saturday, we got a parking for our car quiet easily which was a
surprise. We went to the restaurant upstairs, the first thing we noticed was the
noise. Though Seashell is an expensive restaurant, the noise level was really
high. People were talking all around and there was no noise absorption surface
around. So the ambiance was not what we expected from a good branded restaurant.
In Greames road Sea Shell, we had separating walls that muted sounds a bit,
over here in Velacherry it was open and was disappointing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets come to the food now. We ordered Chicken Briyani, Mutton Briyani and a
barbecue platter (which is shown below)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/seashell_barbeque_platter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The platter came early before Briyani. I see this trend in today
 where the butlers are told to serve the side dish first. Lets say that I had
 ordered a Mutton Briyani with Chicken 65, the Chicken 65 is served first, so
 I start to chew on it, by the time the briyani arrives, I would be low on the
 side dish and may possibly order another one. Nice trick!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we ordered a huge platter, it had barbecued chicken that was good,
 the prawn and mutton was okay too, but the fish barbecued… well, it wasn’t
 nice. If you notice the chicken it had food coloring, which I don’t like, but
 thats how restaurants serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barbecue platter also came with barbecued paneer and other veggies, which
 were okay. The barbecues did complement briyani well. I did not taste the
 Chicken Briyani, I had the mutton. The mutton was really soft and good, but
 the briyani, hmmm… it wasn’t good enough, it wasn’t bad either. The best thing
 was a red chutney they give you in a small cup which you can garnish your
 barbecue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall for a restaurant that charges you extra for an extra mayonnaise, Sea Shell
 is only below okay. They could do a lot more for what they charge.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Review of Kumarakom - Velacherry</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/restaurant/briyani/review/chennai/velacherry/kerala-cuisine/2018/01/06/review-of-kumarakom-velacherry.html"/>
   <updated>2018-01-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/restaurant/briyani/review/chennai/velacherry/kerala-cuisine/2018/01/06/review-of-kumarakom-velacherry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mutton_briyani_in_kumarakom_velacherry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently we went to Kumarakom in Velacherry to see how it is. We ordered few
dishes. We ordered Mutton, Chicken and Egg Briyani. As side we ordered Prawn fry,
Policha Meen, and Chicken 65. So how was it? Read on …..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumarakom positions itself as a Kerala restaurant, and it has got lot of
decorations in it to reflect Kerala spirit, the hotel looks neat and just like
any restaurant in Chennai, its tables were small. We had to constantly move
plates and other dishes to accommodate the side dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its serving of briyani is weird. Biyani no matter what type you eat, is served
with an appalam, lemon pickle and raita. Hmmm thats weird to me. But those side
dishes goes well with Briyani, except for the raita which was not upto the mark,
its curd was very bad quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The briyani is served with meat or eggs cooked in thick gravy that goes to the bottom
of the bown and the rice tops it. One needs to mix it well to have it. The
chicken briyani was okay, but the mutton is mutton briyani tasted well but was
not cooked soft. You have to bite and pull it hard with your teeth to tear it
to sizable pieces to eat. Usually briyani is cooked in such a way that the meat
in it is soft and so one can piece it with hand mix it with rice and eat it,
here thats not the case. And mind you this is a high priced restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were amazed that there was no Kushka, and let me explain why. When you eat chicken
briyani, the rice must have chicken flavor, when you eat mutton briyani the rice
must have absorbed the mutton flavor, and similarly for egg too. Here in
Kumarakom, nope we did not get such flavor. Looks like Kumarakom is cooking
chicken, mutton and egg with a thick paste and thats been put in the bottom of the bowl and
topped with cooked rice. the same rice tops what ever paste is added to the
bowl. Well thats not briyani! Thats cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now coming to the prawn fry, there were more dry seeds, and masala and other
seasoning and garnish in the plate than prawns. The size of the prawn too was tiny and it
wasn’t that good. The prawn did not have prawn flavor. Possibly it was stored
for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policha meen, i.e the fish cooked inside bannana leaf was ok, it was
tender, the masala had soaked well into the outer layers of the fish and was
crispy, and the inner layers were tender. But if you are looking for the fish flavor
hmmmm… no you did not really get it. It was bad in that respect. The fish had a sour
tasting masala coated on top of it,  which tasted well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally coming to Chicken 65. It was just like any other chicken 65, red in
color, boneless but was cooked well and soft. Well billing itself as hifi
restaurant, is it good to add such coloring? You decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tandoori/cooking/food-coloring/2017/12/15/color-of-tandoori-chicken.html&quot;&gt;Color of Tandoori Chicken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
