<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - restaurant</title>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/restaurant/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/restaurant.html"/>
 <updated>2017-12-17T17:01:40+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/restaurant.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Salem R.R Briyani in Medavakkam</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/14/salem-r-r-briyani-in-medavakkam.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-14T16:39:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/14/salem-r-r-briyani-in-medavakkam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salem-rr-biryani-medavakkam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a review of Salem R.R restaurant at Medavkkam. As far as our experience
goes, Salem R.R was first visited when it was in Chitlapakkam near Tambaram East.
People say it was first a parotta shop when there was huge lorry traffic in
Velacherry Tambaram road. We have tasted it parotta and in Chitlapakkam it was
excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then this shop became a Briyani shop too. Though its Briyani is not really good
one, it became famous with low price paying masses because it offered good
quantity of rice compared to other shops. This shop also has prepackaged briyani.
Just walk into the shop pay your bill, walk to briyani counter and you have
briyani to take away in a minute. Definitely the management knows to streamline
process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently visited this hotel in Medavakkam, and to say the truth, this
restaurant is okay. Its clean enough has no fancy paintaings and all those things
to make it feel its posh, but a half chicken briyani now costs Rs 150/-. But
it has good quantity of rice in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time prior the rice quantity was reduced, possibly it was comparable to
A.R. Rahmans quantity, but Salem R.R’s tastes like glorified pulisaadham with
masala and meat added to it, so possibly seeing sales drop they have increased
the rice quantity once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What ever might be the reason, if you are going for briyani taste, then this
restaurant is something that may be avoided, but if you are really hungry and
don’t bother much about the quality then this restaurant can be visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quantity of chicken in briyani too is very less. Not enough meat to go with
every bite, but now possibly seeing Salem R.R and possibly to increase profit,
A.R Rahman too has reduced meat quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A.R.Rahman Briyani is not as good as before</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/13/A-R-Rahman-Briyani-is-not-as-good-as-before.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/13/A-R-Rahman-Briyani-is-not-as-good-as-before</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/a-r-rahman-biriyani-medavakkam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Namma Samayal’s experience with A.R.Rahman briyani. We were dining
in Medavakkam restaurant for a long time, the quality used to be near perfect,
but now it has dropped significantly. Notably the amount of meat in chicken
briyani has dropped significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a chicken briyani used to have nice two huge pieces of meat that was
copious. When we ate we used to have meat in almost every bite, now the meat
has dropped just to  one piece and mostly its the leg piece with little meat
attached to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When A.R Rahman opened in Medavakkam, it was the place to go, but now it has
become just another restaurant which serves just another medium quality briyani
with very less meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its quiet sad that restaurant we cherished for briyani has become like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@karthik_ak/a-r-rahman-briyani-is-good-3ba73621bc32&quot;&gt;A.R.Rahman Briyani is good&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
