<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 <title>Your Title - briyani</title>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/briyani/index.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/briyani.html"/>
 <updated>2018-04-04T08:51:55+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://nammasamayal.github.io/tag/briyani.html</id>
 <author>
   <name>Author Here</name>
 </author>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Review of Kumarakom - Velacherry</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/restaurant/briyani/review/chennai/velacherry/kerala-cuisine/2018/01/06/review-of-kumarakom-velacherry.html"/>
   <updated>2018-01-06T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/restaurant/briyani/review/chennai/velacherry/kerala-cuisine/2018/01/06/review-of-kumarakom-velacherry</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mutton_briyani_in_kumarakom_velacherry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently we went to Kumarakom in Velacherry to see how it is. We ordered few
dishes. We ordered Mutton, Chicken and Egg Briyani. As side we ordered Prawn fry,
Policha Meen, and Chicken 65. So how was it? Read on …..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kumarakom positions itself as a Kerala restaurant, and it has got lot of
decorations in it to reflect Kerala spirit, the hotel looks neat and just like
any restaurant in Chennai, its tables were small. We had to constantly move
plates and other dishes to accommodate the side dish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its serving of briyani is weird. Biyani no matter what type you eat, is served
with an appalam, lemon pickle and raita. Hmmm thats weird to me. But those side
dishes goes well with Briyani, except for the raita which was not upto the mark,
its curd was very bad quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The briyani is served with meat or eggs cooked in thick gravy that goes to the bottom
of the bown and the rice tops it. One needs to mix it well to have it. The
chicken briyani was okay, but the mutton is mutton briyani tasted well but was
not cooked soft. You have to bite and pull it hard with your teeth to tear it
to sizable pieces to eat. Usually briyani is cooked in such a way that the meat
in it is soft and so one can piece it with hand mix it with rice and eat it,
here thats not the case. And mind you this is a high priced restaurant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were amazed that there was no Kushka, and let me explain why. When you eat chicken
briyani, the rice must have chicken flavor, when you eat mutton briyani the rice
must have absorbed the mutton flavor, and similarly for egg too. Here in
Kumarakom, nope we did not get such flavor. Looks like Kumarakom is cooking
chicken, mutton and egg with a thick paste and thats been put in the bottom of the bowl and
topped with cooked rice. the same rice tops what ever paste is added to the
bowl. Well thats not briyani! Thats cheating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now coming to the prawn fry, there were more dry seeds, and masala and other
seasoning and garnish in the plate than prawns. The size of the prawn too was tiny and it
wasn’t that good. The prawn did not have prawn flavor. Possibly it was stored
for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The policha meen, i.e the fish cooked inside bannana leaf was ok, it was
tender, the masala had soaked well into the outer layers of the fish and was
crispy, and the inner layers were tender. But if you are looking for the fish flavor
hmmmm… no you did not really get it. It was bad in that respect. The fish had a sour
tasting masala coated on top of it,  which tasted well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally coming to Chicken 65. It was just like any other chicken 65, red in
color, boneless but was cooked well and soft. Well billing itself as hifi
restaurant, is it good to add such coloring? You decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reference&quot;&gt;Reference&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/tandoori/cooking/food-coloring/2017/12/15/color-of-tandoori-chicken.html&quot;&gt;Color of Tandoori Chicken&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Salem R.R Briyani in Medavakkam</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/14/salem-r-r-briyani-in-medavakkam.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-14T16:39:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/14/salem-r-r-briyani-in-medavakkam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/salem-rr-biryani-medavakkam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a review of Salem R.R restaurant at Medavkkam. As far as our experience
goes, Salem R.R was first visited when it was in Chitlapakkam near Tambaram East.
People say it was first a parotta shop when there was huge lorry traffic in
Velacherry Tambaram road. We have tasted it parotta and in Chitlapakkam it was
excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then this shop became a Briyani shop too. Though its Briyani is not really good
one, it became famous with low price paying masses because it offered good
quantity of rice compared to other shops. This shop also has prepackaged briyani.
Just walk into the shop pay your bill, walk to briyani counter and you have
briyani to take away in a minute. Definitely the management knows to streamline
process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently visited this hotel in Medavakkam, and to say the truth, this
restaurant is okay. Its clean enough has no fancy paintaings and all those things
to make it feel its posh, but a half chicken briyani now costs Rs 150/-. But
it has good quantity of rice in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some time prior the rice quantity was reduced, possibly it was comparable to
A.R. Rahmans quantity, but Salem R.R’s tastes like glorified pulisaadham with
masala and meat added to it, so possibly seeing sales drop they have increased
the rice quantity once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What ever might be the reason, if you are going for briyani taste, then this
restaurant is something that may be avoided, but if you are really hungry and
don’t bother much about the quality then this restaurant can be visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quantity of chicken in briyani too is very less. Not enough meat to go with
every bite, but now possibly seeing Salem R.R and possibly to increase profit,
A.R Rahman too has reduced meat quantity.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A.R.Rahman Briyani is not as good as before</title>
   <link href="http://nammasamayal.github.io/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/13/A-R-Rahman-Briyani-is-not-as-good-as-before.html"/>
   <updated>2017-12-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://example.com/briyani/restaurant/review/chennai/medavakkam/2017/12/13/A-R-Rahman-Briyani-is-not-as-good-as-before</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/a-r-rahman-biriyani-medavakkam.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is Namma Samayal’s experience with A.R.Rahman briyani. We were dining
in Medavakkam restaurant for a long time, the quality used to be near perfect,
but now it has dropped significantly. Notably the amount of meat in chicken
briyani has dropped significantly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before a chicken briyani used to have nice two huge pieces of meat that was
copious. When we ate we used to have meat in almost every bite, now the meat
has dropped just to  one piece and mostly its the leg piece with little meat
attached to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When A.R Rahman opened in Medavakkam, it was the place to go, but now it has
become just another restaurant which serves just another medium quality briyani
with very less meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its quiet sad that restaurant we cherished for briyani has become like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@karthik_ak/a-r-rahman-briyani-is-good-3ba73621bc32&quot;&gt;A.R.Rahman Briyani is good&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
</feed>
